Guide to the Marvin Mirsky Papers 1941-2014
University of Chicago Library
- Series III: Course Materials
  - University of Chicago, Fine Arts Program, correspondence, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - English L102 Poetry, notes, reading lists, examinations, 1954-1960 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - English L102 Short Stories, notes, examinations, 1957-1960 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - English 250 The Nature of Satire, notes, student roster, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Fine Arts II Literature, reading lists, 1958-1961 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Fine Arts 067 Biblical Themes in Modern Literature, notes, reading list, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Fine Arts N270 Contemporary Fiction, notes, articles, student rosters, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Fine Arts N281 Existential Literature, notes, articles, reading lists, student rosters, 1961-1963 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Fine Arts N283 The Novel: Neglected Masterpieces, notes, reading lists, student mailing lists, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Fine Arts N284 Satire: Variations on a Theme, reading lists, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Humanities 194 Renaissance Literature, notes, reading list, assignments, 1958-1960 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Humanities 266 The Picaresque Novel, reading lists, assignments, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Humanities 125 Human Being and Citizen, paper assignment, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Literature courses, notes, correspondence, 1958-1962 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Literature courses, notes, correspondence, 2000-2005 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Literature courses, final examinations undated (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Recent and Contemporary Fiction, reading lists, roster, 2005-2011 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Recent and Contemporary Fiction, notes, correspondence, 2010-2011 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Recent and Contemporary Fiction, reading lists, correspondence, 2010-2012 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Recent and Contemporary Fiction, student mailing lists, correspondence, 2008-2013 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Recent and Contemporary Fiction, reading lists, student mailing lists, correspondence, 2007-2014 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Conrad, Joseph, reading lists, 1993-1994 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - James, Henry II & III, reading list, student mailing list, 1986-1994 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Kafka, Major Works, reading lists, student mailing list, correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Proust, Marcel: Remembrance of Things Past, course materials, correspondence, schedules, 1983-1984 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Tolstoy, Leo: War and Peace, reading lists, student mailing list, correspondence, 2007-2010 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - The Bible, reading lists, student mailing lists, correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Comic Apocalypse, notes, articles, student rosters, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Innovations in the Novel, reading lists, bibliographies, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Innovations in the Drama, reading lists, undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Introduction to Literature, assignments, correspondence, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Masterworks of 20th Century Fiction, notes, reading list, 2000-2005 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Minor Masters of the 20th Century, reading lists, student mailing list, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - The Other Russians I, notes, reading lists, student mailing list, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - The Other Russians II, notes, reading list, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Three Postmodern Writers, notes, reading list, 2003-2004 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Indiana University, lecture notes, correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Assorted reading lists and student mailing lists, 1995-2009 (Box 32, Folder 6)
- Series IV: Reading and Film Groups
  - Aspen-in-Chicago, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Book Club, 2007-2011 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Dune Acres Book Group, 1993-1994 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Dune Acres Reading Group, 1996-2012 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Evanston Film Group, 2005-2010 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Gary Reading Group, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Glencoe Film Group, 2005-2010 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Near North Book Group, 1996-1997 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - North Shore Film Group, 2011 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - North Shore Reading Group, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - North Shore Reading Group, 1964-1965 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - North Shore Reading Group, 1970-1971 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - North Shore Reading Group, Marcel Proust, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - North Shore Reading Group, Tolstoy: Anna Karenina, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - North Side Theatre Group, undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - North Suburban Book Group, 1996-2010 (Box 33, Folder 4)
- Series V: Articles
  - “Human Rights,” ACLU, 1957-1958 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Existentialism, notes, articles, 1958-1960 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - “Infant Data,” “Vaccinations,” 1958-1961 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Book Reviews, notes, articles, 1966-1977 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - “Naked Censorship,” Chicago Review Reader, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Hyde Park Herald, March 12, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Book Reviews, 1962-1999 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Magazine articles, 1984-2000 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - “God’s Librarians,” “Muslim Publics,” “Health Care Abroad,” 2009-2011 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Book Reviews, undated (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - “Books of Special Interest,” articles, pamphlets, undated (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Existentialism, articles, undated (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - “Author’s Preface,” Henry Fielding, undated (Box 33, Folder 17)
- Series VI: Personal
  - Poetry sketchbook, 1941-1945 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - ACLU, correspondence, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Notes on literature, carbon copies, 1957-1961 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Letters, carbon copies, 1960-1961 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Editing, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Wallant, Edward Lewis Paper, drafts, correspondence, 1962-1966 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Zasloff, Karen, letter, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1997-2013 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Literary analysis papers, undated (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Portraits, undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Jayne Anne Philips: Shelter, Newspaper Clippings, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - JM Coetzee: The Master of Petersburg, Newspaper Clipping, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Vassily Aksyonov: Generations of Winter, Newspaper Clippings, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - John Updike: In the Beauty of the Lillies, Newspaper Clippings, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Thomas Mann: Buddenbrooks, Newspaper Clipping, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Ernest Hemmingway: The Sun Also Rises, Newspaper Clippings, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Gabriel Garcia Marquez: Of Love and Other Demons, Newspaper Clipping, 1995-1996 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Roddy Doyle: The Woman who walked into Doors, Newspaper Clippings, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Carol Shields: The Stone Diaries, Newspaper Clippings 1994 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Salman Rushdie: East, West (stories) Newspaper Clippings, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Kenzaburo Oe: teach Us to Outgrow Our Madness, Newspaper Clippings, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Cormac McCarthy: The Crossing, Newspaper Clippings, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Tony Kushner: Angels in America, Newspaper Clippings 1994 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Ivan Klima: Waiting for the Dark, Waiting for the Light, Newspaper Clipping, 1994-1995 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Joseph Heller: Closing Time, Newspaper Clippings, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - EL Doctorow: The Waterworks, Newspaper Clipping, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Tom Stoppard: Arcadia, Newspaper Clippings, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Salman Rushdie: The Moor’s Last Sign, Newspaper Clippings, 1995-1996 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Philip Roth: Sabbath’s Theatre, Newspaper Clipping, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Julian Banres: Cross Channel, Newspaper Clippings, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Gary Reading Group, Contemporary Fiction-Drama- Summer, Newspaper Clippings, 1964 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Legal, etc. Newspaper Clippings, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - Infant Data, Newspaper Clippings, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Books, Reviews, etc. (D), Newspaper Clippings 1953? (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - North Shore Group, Newspaper Clippings, 1962 (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - Woody Allen: Husbands and Wives, Crimes and Misdemeanors, Newspaper Clippings, 1989-1992 (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - Woody Allen: Husbands and Wives; Alice; Crimes and Misdemeanors, Newspaper Clippings (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - Provst: Request for Tapes, Transcripts. Newspaper Clippings, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 28)
  - Provst Course: Materials, Newspaper Clippings,, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 29)
  - ND585. Dostoevsky I: Cana P, The Idiot and Selected Short Works. Class Documents, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - ND571. Selected Works of Charles Dickens: Winter 1980. Characters in Bleak House Chart (Box 35, Folder 31)
  - EL Doctorow: City of God, Newspaper Articles, 2000 (Box 35, Folder 32)
  - Doctorow, EL. Newspaper Articles, 1975-1989 (Box 35, Folder 33)
  - Dickens. Newspaper Clipping, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 34)
  - Zadie SmithL NW. Newspaper Clippings, 2010-2013 (Box 35, Folder 35)
  - Woody Allen: celebrity, Oversized Newspaper Clipping, 1998 (Box 35, Folder 36)
  - Newspaper Clipping, 1958. From the University of Chicago: Miscellaneous (Seminars, Notices, Notes on Lectures, etc.) (Box 35, Folder 37)
  - Tolstoy: War and peace, 2007-2010, articles (Box 35, Folder 38)
  - Tim Robbins: Cradle Will Rock, 1999-2000. Articles (Box 35, Folder 39)
  - Thomas Pynchon: Inherent Vice, 2009-2010. Articles (Box 35, Folder 40)
  - The New York Review Articles, 2004-2008 (Box 35, Folder 41)
  - Terrence Malick: The Thin Red Line (1998), 1998-1999. Oversized Articles (Box 35, Folder 42)
  - Susan Sontag: In America, Articles 2000 (Box 35, Folder 43)
  - Peter Carey: Parrot and Olivier in America, 2010-2012 (Box 35, Folder 44)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1999. Martin Scorsese: Bringing Out the Dead (Box 35, Folder 45)
  - Newspaper Articles, Jonathan Demme: Beloved, 1998 (Box 35, Folder 46)
  - Newspaper Clipping, 2008. JMG Le Clezio: The Prospector (Box 35, Folder 47)
- Series VII: Restricted
  - Student papers on Robbe-Grillet, 1968, restricted until 2048 (Box 36, Folder 1)